ETHAN CAFFREY

Sixmilebridge, Clare | P: +353 831550159 | ethancaff@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/ethan-caffrey-0b2976136 | Website: https://kahfree.github.io/

PERSONAL PROFILE

Aspiring software developer who is self-motivated with a passion for programming. Loves to work in a team. Has excellent critical thinking and analytical skills.

SUMMARY

Graduated with a First Class Honours in Software Development from the Technological University of the Shannon (TUS). Developed excellent critical thinking skills through my degree. Improved my soft skills significantly through my experience as a sales assistant at Dunnes Stores. My determination and dedication are highlighted by my achievement of a black belt in taekwondo. I have developed strong time management, team work, and critical thinking skills during my internship with ChannelAdvisor. Self-motivated. A Team Player with a strong work ethic.

EXPERIENCE

ERICSSON

Software Engineer Jul 2023 – Present

Athlone, Ireland

UNIJOBS DAC

Learning Support Unit Tutor

Oct 2021 – Feb 2022, Sep 2022 – Apr 2023

Limerick, Ireland

- Tutored 1st, 2nd, and 3rd year students in all IT modules.
- Developed teaching skills in both individual and group settings.

CHANNELADVISOR

Software Engineer Intern

Mar 2022 - Aug 2022

Limerick, Ireland

- Developed robust code to handle REST request and responses in C# and .NET
- Worked with Azure DevOps and to deliver CI/CD
- Followed agile workflow with scrum and sprint reviews
- Worked with javascript for frontend, specflow for testing, and redis for caching data.

DUNNES STORES

Sales Assistant

Shannon, Clare, Ireland Mar 2021 – Dec 2021

- Delivering superb service by engaging with customers.
- Ensuring that visual and brand standards area maintained on the sales floor.
- Ensuring that promotional activity is delivered.
- Stock inventory to the shop floor.

FIVERR

Website Developer / Freelancer

July 2020 - Dec 2020

- Build website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Work closely with client to collect requirements and ensure project quality.
- Understanding the importance of communication to build the project.
- Currently inactive to prioritise academic studies.

EDUCATION

TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY OF THE SHANNON - Limerick, Ireland

Bachelor of Science (Honours) in Software Development

Award: First Class Honours H1 (1.1)

GPA: 79.71%

ADDITIONAL

Technical: SQL, PHP, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, C#, Python, C++, Git, Java

Certifications & Training: C++ (Codecademy), Git (Codecademy), Command Line (Codecademy), SQL Fundamentals

(SoloLearn).

PROJECTS

FOCAL

- Computer-Vision based mobile application for exercise analysis.
- Final year project as part of the software development course.
- Wrote in Kotlin and utilizes the Firebase Realtime Database.

TREATY MARKET

- Responsive PHP webapp build using the CodeIgniter framework.
- Functional e-commerce website with log in/ log out functionality and cart functionality.
- Admin account features with full Product CRUD.

TRAFFIC LIGHTS

- Constructed working simulation of traffic lights using an Arduino.
- Wired with LEDs and a light sensor, to change durations depending on the light level.
- Coded using the Arduino Programming language, which is based on C and C++.

STUDENT ASSIGNEMNT SYSTEM

- Developed a Student Assignment system using C# WinForms.
- Application has a Student, Lecturer, and Administrator dashboard.

References can be given upon request

2019 - 2023